

SIMON MCMAHON

0490 066 236

simon.nathan.mcmahon@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/simon-mcmahon/

PERSONAL STATEMENT

As an experienced academic tutor and business owner, I possess **clear communication skills**. As a programmer and mathematically-minded problem solver, I possess **strong technical skills**, with a deep understanding of mathematical ideas and methods. I am an experienced team player and strive to **add value** wherever I work.

I'd love to have a chat about how I could work for you, so you can get the best out of your business.

SKILLS

Modelling and Programming
(MATLAB, Python, R, SQL, Excel VBA, git)
Problem-solving mindset
Research and Data Analysis

Project Management
Explanation of Technical Material
Client acquisition / communication / management
Direct sales and marketing

EDUCATION & AWARDS

University of Queensland — Bachelor of Mathematics

2013-2016 and 2017- Present

Studying (graduation planned Semester 2, 2017) an undergraduate degree in Mathematics with a focus on applied concepts such as statistics, operations research, practical optimization and financial mathematics.

University of Queensland — Vice Chancellor Scholarship

Awarded a \$12 000 p.a. scholarship based on academic merit. It is the highest value undergraduate scholarship the University of Queensland awards.

All Saints Anglican School — Queensland Certificate of Education

2012

Graduated with an exit mark of an OP1 (ATAR 99.95). This is the highest possible exit mark.

WORK EXPERIENCE

University of Queensland — Casual Academic Tutor

Semester 1, 2017 - Present

Throughout 2017, I was brought on as a tutor for mathematics at the university. This involved presenting and explaining mathematics to a tutorial of 25 people multiple times each week, as well as marking assignments and providing feedback.

MIGHTY MINDS — Numeracy Consultant (Holiday Casual Work)

Jan 2017 - Present

MIGHTY MINDS is the **largest education consulting company in Queensland.** They provide resources, testing and marking and workshops for many QLD schools. I was tasked with developing their Numeracy resources.

Altius Tutoring — Founder and Head Tutor

2013 - Present

I started a private tutoring company specialising in 1-on-1 tutoring for senior school mathematics, physics and chemistry. Within this role I developed **excellent communication skills** - routinely extracting and dissecting the essence of a complex concept **and explaining it in plain English**. I also gained valuable skills **in sales, marketing** and **scheduling**.

EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Pro Bono Econos - Volunteer Consultant

Semester 1, 2016

I joined the team in Semester 1 2016 and analysed the economic impact of proposed regional innovations centres in Queensland. I learnt a great deal about assessing client needs in consulting and developed a passion applying mathematics in a real-world environment.

University of Queensland - Student Leader

Semester 1, 2016

University of Queensland - Science Ambassador

March. 2016

Represented the University of Queensland in a public capacity at the World Science fair.

Scouts Australia — National Youth Council

2010-2013

Represented the youth of **Scouts Australia at a national level.** The role involved running meetings and working with a remote team separated across Australia.

PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATIONS

SSA (Statistics Society of Australia) & AMSI (Australian Mathematical Sciences Institute)

HOBBIES/INTERESTS

Hiking and bushwalking / Cycling / Board Games / Ultimate Disc

REFEREES AVAILABLE UPON REQUEST.